cigna.com 2001-06-07

# CIGNA.com - Privacy Statement

May 14, 2001

Please read carefully.

  * What kind of information does CIGNA.com collect?
  * What do you do with the information you collect about me?
  * What if I need to correct or remove information about me?
  * What if I don't want you to collect, use and distribute my information?
  * About e-mail
  * How secure is CIGNA.com?
  * What about the links on your site? Are they secure?
  * I'm not a U.S. customer. How do I fit into your privacy policies?
  * I've switched to another company. What will you do with my information?
  * Why is this Privacy Statement important to me?

We know that when you visit us at CIGNA.com, you depend on us to be as diligent about protecting your privacy on-line as we've always been in our more traditional interactions with you. We also know that you rely on us to provide products and services that meet each of your unique needs. To do both, we need to gather—and protect—certain information about you.

What kind of information does CIGNA.com collect?

We've designed our Web site to capture two types of information: automatic tracking and individualized. The first allows us to see which topics interest you most; the second helps us service your accounts.

**Automatic tracking information** is gathered by following your "footsteps" through CIGNA.com. When you enter our site, you can choose one of four routes to information tailored to a specific group: Consumer, Professional, Provider or Global. The route you—and other visitors—choose tells us a little something about the people who visit our site. We use aggregate numbers to compile statistics, monitor trends and track site usage. We also use the information to make sure our technology is compatible with yours. We're then better able to offer products and services that match your needs.

**Individualized information** can be anything you've provided to CIGNA.com that identifies you or your accounts. For example: Your name, social security number, birth date, address and names of your dependents are types of individualized information. We use this information to service your accounts. It's our policy to send and receive individualized information through encrypted channels only. 

To use our secure services, "cookies" must be enabled. Cookies are small pieces of software that remain activated during your session in a secure area, then are deactivated when you log off.

What do you do with the information you collect about me?

We will **not** sell, rent or license your individualized information furnished by you to CIGNA.com unless you authorize it. But we may need to use it within the CIGNA family of affiliate companies or with a third party vendor to perform administrative, technical, hosting, marketing or other functions that help us manage the site while providing service to you. Our third party vendors subscribe to the same privacy practices as CIGNA.com.

Except as noted above, we will not release individualized information to any other party unless required to do so by government authorities or legal process or as otherwise permitted by law. 

What if I need to correct or remove information about me?

You can contact your employer or account representative directly. Please do not e-mail individualized information unless you do so through a secure channel. We have a policy that prohibits us from communicating individualized information through non-secure e-mail.

What if I don't want you to collect, use and distribute my information?

If you don't want CIGNA.com to collect, use and distribute information about you, there are always traditional means of communication available to you. Simply pick up the phone or send your questions, comments and specific information by regular mail.

About e-mail

From time to time we may send informational, educational or promotional materials to you at the e-mail address you've provided. 

Please remember that e-mail messages can be viewed by other Internet users while in transit. If you have individualized information to communicate, please contact your local customer service representative or e-mail us a request for your customer service representative to contact you.

How secure is CIGNA.com?

Your individualized information at CIGNA.com is protected from unauthorized access by a secure firewall and security infrastructure. During transmission, your privacy is protected by Secure Socket Layer 128 bit encrypting software. Then when the information is received, we employ extensive physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to maintain the security of your information. CIGNA.com also conducts periodic reviews of its Web security to ensure that our electronic security safeguards remain up-to-date and effective.

What about the links on your site? Are they secure?

Because we don't own or control all the sites linked from CIGNA.com, we can't guarantee they're secure; therefore, we can not assume responsibility for all their privacy practices. If you enroll with a company that is not affiliated with CIGNA.com or any CIGNA company, we urge you to review the privacy policies of any of the Web sites you visit once you leave CIGNA.com.

I'm not a U.S. customer. How do I fit into your privacy policies?

Your continued use of CIGNA.com from within the European Union ("EU") or other non-U.S. country means that you are giving your consent to have your individualized information processed outside the EU or other country in accordance with the protection described in this statement. 

I've switched my coverage to another company. What will you do with my information?

We will continue to treat your individualized information with the same confidentiality and respect we extend to all our valuable customers.

Why is this Privacy Statement important to me?

Your visit to CIGNA.com and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Statement and our Legal Disclaimer/Conditions of Use including limitations of damages, application of the law of the State of Delaware and exclusive jurisdiction of Delaware. 

This statement is applicable only to information collected from you during your visit to the CIGNA.com Web site. We will display a prominent notice on the CIGNA.com home page whenever this Privacy Statement is updated or changed and you should check our Privacy Statement periodically. By choosing to continue usage of CIGNA.com, you agree to the terms of the Privacy Statement. 

If you have any questions of comments concerning this Statement, please contact us at CIGNA.com by postal mail at:

CIGNA.com Privacy Statement  
c/o E-commerce Office  
900 Cottage Grove Road, S113  
Hartford, CT 06152-2113

Thanks for taking the time to read this Privacy Statement.
